Guide to the Don Patinkin Papers, 1870-1995
Don Patinkin papers 1870-1995
- Keynes and the History of Monetary Theory, 1870-1994and undated (Bulk 1930-1989)
  - Raw Materials
    - Keynes' Review - Raw Material, 1911-1930
    - Compensated Dollar -Used Fisher Reprints,1913
    - Keynes' Review Raw Materials, 1921-1936, (3 folders)
      - Keynes' Raw Materials H-N, 1922-1970, (2 folders)
      - O-Z, 1923-1980, (2 folders)
      - A-G, 1924-1986, (2 folders)
    - Swedish Correspondence, 1924-1977
    - Miscellaneous,1925
    - G. Myrdal, Prisbildnihgsproblemet Och Foranderligheten,1927
    - Bulletin of National Industrial Conference Board, 1927-1938 (Box 12)
    - Terms of Neutrality and Veil, A-Jn, 1928-1988, (2 folders)
    - Ministry of Labor Gazette, 1929
    - Kalecki - Articles by various authors, 1929-1951, (2 folders)
    - Anticipations of General Theory - Raw Materials, 1929-1981, (2 folders)
    - Terms of Neutrality and Veil, K-L, 1929-1933, (2 folders)
    - Lecture Notes, Cambridge: Salant, Bryce, 1930-1935
    - Lecture Notes, Cambridge: Tarshis, Bryce, Falgatter, 1930-1935
    - Minutes of Evidence: Committee on Finance and Industry,1931, (3 folders)
    - Gunnar Myrdal, 1931
    - Patinkin - Wicksell and Keynes,1930 (Box 13)
    - Harris Foundation Roundtable,1931
    - Minutes on Evidence, Committee on Finance and Industry,1931, (3 folders)
    - B. Ohlin: Courses and Phases of World Economic Depression,1931
    - Keynes Papers - Unpublished Materials, 1931-1935
    - Keynes Objective Notes, 1931-1934, (2 folders)
    - Compensated Dollar, 1933
    - Keynes Notes, 1931-1934
    - Harris Foundation Reports, 1931-1932
    - Keynes Lecture Notes R. B.Bryce,1932,1933,1934 (Box 14)
    - Anticipations Raw Materials,1929-1981
    - Lecture Notes, Cambridge, 1930-1935 Salant, Bryce
    - Keynes Lecture Notes, R.B. Bryce, 1932-1933
    - Cambridge Lecture Notes, 1932-1936, (3 folders)
    - Keynes and Kahn Lecture Notes, Tarshis, 1932-1934
    - Keynes Lecture Notes, 1932-1935, Falgatter, Tarshis
    - Keynes and the Swedish school, 1932-1976, (2 folders)
    - Keynes lecture notes by Salant,1933
    - Hawtrey-Robertson Correspondence,1933
    - Translations of Ohlin's1933Article
    - Cambridge Lectures,1933
    - Keynes Lecture Notes, 1933-1935
    - Keynes, Robertson, Shove lectures, 1933-1935, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Other Michael Kalecki articles, 1933-1988, (2 folders)
    - Gunnar Myrdal's Finanspolitkens Ekonomiska,1934-1986
    - Swedish committee on unemployment,1934-1935
    - Ohlin1934Report
    - Swedish Committee on Unemployment, 1934-1935 Ohlin, (2 folders)
    - Swedish Committee on Unemployment, 1934-1935Myrdal, (2 folders)
    - Compensated Dollar/ Other Congressional Hearings, 1934-1977
    - Compensated Dollar - A. R. Wallace Book
    - Compensated Dollar - not used
    - Keynes General Theory - 1st proof ,1935, (2 folders)
    - 1935 Report
    - Ohlin - Reprints, Reports, and Lectures, 1936-1979, (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Raw Material 3,1937, (2 folders)
    - Kalecki - Correspondence, 1937-1983
    - Keynes - Raw Materials, 1938-1979, (2 folders)
    - Michael Kalecki Articles, 1939-1981, (2 folders)
    - Keynes and the Swedish School, 1942-1979, (3 folders)
    - Joan Robinson, 1946 (Box 17)
    - Towards a Bibliography of John Maynard Keynes, 1950-1977, (2 folders)
    - Keynes and the Scandinavian School, S-Z, 1958-1976, (3 folders)
    - Supply Function, 1962-1972
    - Anticipations of the GT? The Problems Defined, 1966-1975
    - Facsimile,1967
    - Johannsen, 1973
    - Leijenhufuud Disequilibrium Approach, 1974-1978
    - Keynes Raw Material - general and working notes, 1970-1978
    - Interview with Paul Samuelson; Includes Cassette,1972
    - Keynes Raw Material,1974
    - Ohlin Correspondence, 1975-1979
    - Keynes Raw Material, 1919-1974
    - Axel Leijonhuvfud: Disequilibrium Approach, 1974-1978
    - Econometric Society Lecture,1975
    - After the GT: Critics, Answers,1975 (Box 18)
    - George Garvey, Keynes and the Econometric Activists of Pre-Hitler Germany, 1975
    - Econometric Society Lecture,1975
    - Stenogram of Conference on Keynes, Cambridge and the GT,1975
    - Keynes' Monetary Thought, 1976
    - Keynes and Econometrics, 1976
    - Keynes Conference,1976
    - Landsner - The New Economics in Sweden,1977, (2 folders)
    - The General Theory and After, ed. Moggridge1977
    - Interpretation, 1977-1988
    - Hahn Volume, 1978
    - Citatious data re: Keynes and Keynesianism, 1979-1982
    - Future Corrections to Keynes and Econometrics, 1980
    - 1980 Palgrave (Box 19)
    - Interpretation, General Theory:
      - 1980 (M-Z), (2 folders)
      - 1986 (A-G)
    - Keynesian Cross,1987
    - B. Ohlin, "Courses and Phases of World Economic Depression,"1931(1987)
    - Keynes Stages of Life,1987
    - Chronology of General Theory,1990
    - Compensated Dollar: Further Work and Changes,1993
    - "Three Controversial Notes on General Theory,"1994
    - Keynes's Uncertain Revolution, 1994, (1 vol.)
  - Course Materials Subseries
    (Chiefly lectures and seminars)
    - History of Monetary Theory From 1898 to 1938 (Box 20)
    - Keynes Conference Papers
    - Keynes Conference Final Manuscript - Correspondence with Participants
    - Lectures on Anticipation,1978
    - Seminar in the History of Modern Monetary Thought,1982, (3 folders)
    - Seminar in the History of Modern Monetary Thought - Original,1982, (3 folders)
    - Seminar - Monetary,1982
    - Materials for Lectures,1982
    - Seminar on Keynes,1982(2 of 3 folders)
    - Seminar on Keynes,1982(3 of 3 folders) (Box 21)
    - Seminar: Development of Keynes' Monetary Thought - Classroom Copy/Notes, (2 folders)
    - Seminar: History of Monetary Theory,1982
    - Seminar: Development of Monetary Theory,1987, (2 folders)
    - Seminar: History of Monetary Theory: The Pre-Keynesian Literature,1989
    - Seminar: History of Modern Monetary Theory: The Pre-Keynesian Literature, (3 folders)
    - Seminar on the Development of Keynes' Monetary Thought,1990, (2 folders)
    - Selected Papers on Economic Theory
    - Cassette Tapes (7)
  - Manuscripts and Notes
    - Some Basic Ideas in Keynesian Theory, 1958 (Box 22)
    - A Restatement of Keynesian Economics, 1950s?
    - Comments on Friedman's Reply
    - Keynes and Econometrics
    - Keynes and Econometrics, 1976, (2 folders)
    - Work in Progress
    - "A Study of Keynes' Theory of Effective Demand," 1979, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous: Student Reading Notes, 1978-1980
    - Anticipations of General Theory, 1980
    - Anticipations of General Theory - Working Copy,1980
    - Anticipations of General Theory, 1982, (3 folders)
    - Manuscripts,1982 (Box 23)
    - Anticipations of General Theory, 1982, (4 folders)
    - Critique JMK,1985
    - Palgrave: Keynes
    - Schabas: Hope
    - Facsimile General Theory: Comments
    - Facsimile General Theory: Long Version
    - Palgrave: Keynes
    - Keynes Lecture Revisions,1989
    - Keynes and Current Economy
    - Historiography of Economics- Changes
    - Keynes and his Interpreters, (2 folders)
    - Friedman on the Quantity Theory and Keynesian Economics, Continued
    - Manuscripts (Box 24)
    - Palgrave Entry - Walras's Law
    - Palgrave - Keynes' Revisions
    - Meltzer - Reply: Raw Materials
    - Compensated Dollar - Revisions and Correspondence
    - On the Development of Keynes' Monetary Thought, (3 folders)
    - Keynes' Monetary Thought - Reviews
    - A Restatement of Keynesian Economics
    - Allan - Keynes: Further Changes
    - Book: Keynes and his Interpreters
- Correspondence, 1930-1995and undated (Bulk 1950-1995)
  Contains scattered files of biographical data in addition to professional correspondence, which includes recommendations, permissions, and purchases. There are also some folders of clippings, book orders, and some photographs. This series reflects the complex and sometimes chronologically overlapping filing structures that Patinkin himself established. As much as possible, these filing systems were left intact, but to avoid excessive overlap some chronological re-organization was necessary. With a few exceptions, the arrangement within filing groups is alphabetical. File folders representing one person's or one institution's correspondence with Patinkin may appear in several physical locations depending on the chronological periods involved. There is one indexed subseries in which Patinkin used codes representing dates; this has been left untouched.
  - 1930-1968and undated
    - AB/MIP, 1953-1962, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - American Economic Association, 1952
    - Amitsur
    - Archibald and Lipsey,1958
    - Aren Committee,1955
    - Arrow, Kenneth J., 1950-1964
    - Bahral, Uri, 1957, Dec.-1963, Apr.
    - Bahral, Uri, 1961
    - Bain, Joe S., 1948
    - BAJT
    - Ball, R. J., 1958-1959
    - Bank of Israel Advisory Committee, 1957, Nov.-1968, Dec.
    - Bank of Israel Advisory Committee, 1959, Jan.-1963, Dec.
    - Banking, 1958, Feb.-May
    - Barkai, Haim, 1957
    - BARTH
    - Barzel, 1957, 1963
    - Baumol, 1953-1959
    - Becker, Gary S., 1950
    - Bekins, 1962
    - Bell, Phillip, 1960
    - Beza and Peskin,1960
    - Biography and Pictures, 1960, Aug.-1962, Jan.(Yehuda Grunfeld)
    - Biography - Final, 1960, March-1962, May(Yehuda Grunfeld)
    - Bonne, 1950-1959
    - Book and Reprint Orders,1959, Jun.-1963, Dec.
    - Bowen, Howard L., 1950
    - Bronfrenbrenner, 1948-1955
    - Brunner, 1949-1950
    - Bruno, 1962
    - Buchanan, Jim, 1953-1962
    - Cagan, 1954-1955
    - Cartel Article, 1946-1947
    - Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Sciences, 1961, Sept.-Nov.
    - Christ, Carl, 1950-1957
    - Clower, 1958-1962
    - Committee on Halting the Monetary Spread, 1962, Dec. (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1968and undated
    - Committee on Matters of National Accounts, 1959, Mar.-Apr.
    - Correspondence, 1958, Dec.-1959, Dec.
    - Correspondence, 1960, Dec.-1961, April
    - Correspondence, 1961, Oct.-1963, Jan.
    - Correspondence and Press Clippings,1960, (2 folders)
    - Correspondence and Press Clippings, 1961, Feb.-1962, July
    - Correspondence re: Dept. of Economics Courses, 1959, Feb.-1961, Jan.
    - Cowles Commission: Simpson, 1933-1959
    - Creamer, Daniel, 1956
    - DeJong, 1952-1956
    - Domas, 1948-1950
    - Early Draft and Final Draft of Talk Given by Patinkin at Beit Berl, 1960, June
    - Econometric Society,1953
    - Econometric Society, 1958, Dec.-1964, Jan.
    - Econometric Society - Budget, 1961, Nov.-1962, March
    - Econometric Society - General, 1961, Aug.-1962, Jan.
    - Econometric Society - Meetings, 1961, Oct.-1962, Jan.
    - Econometric Society - Theil, 1961, July-Dec.
    - Econometrica articles, 1948-1951
    - Efronmson, C. W., 1949-1951
    - Eisenstadt, 1957-1958
    - Eisner, 1964
    - Ellis, Howard, 1952-1956
    - Ellis, Howard, 1961, June-Sept.
    - Fellner, William, 1957
    - Ferber, Robert and Marianne, 1947-1955
    - Finance Ministry, 1952-1954
    - Ford, James, 1957
    - Foreign Currency Committee,1953
    - Fort, Donald, 1950, 1959 (Box 27)
    - Friedman, Milton, 1948-1959
    - General and Personal Correspondence, 1956, Apr.-1957, Oct.,Including 1953, June
    - Paper, "Monetary and Price Development in Israel: 1949-1953"
    - Ginsberg, 1948-1952
    - Ginzberg, Eli, 1962, Feb.-May
    - Glasser, 1953
    - Gogerty and Winston, 1962-1963
    - Goldberger
    - Graziani, 1957-1958
    - Grunfeld Festschrift: Measurement in Economics, 1960, Sept.-1962, Nov.
    - Grunfeld, Yehuda 1958, Aug.-1961, Jun.
    - Grunfeld, Yehuda, Article, 1960, July-1961, Dec.
    - Grunfeld, Yehuda, Funeral Obituary, Memorial Papers, 1960, July-1962, July
    - Gurley, 1960-1963
    - Hahn, 1951-1959
    - Hahn, F. H., 1961, Nov.-1962, April
    - Hansen, Bert, 1952-1957
    - Hasida, Aug. 1961-1962,July
    - Hebrew University, 1958-1960
    - Hebrew University Correspondence - General, 1959, Jan.-May
    - Hebrew Univ. Departmental Matters,1958, Jun.-1959, Feb.
    - Hebrew Univ. Departmental Seminars and Summer Workshops, 1958, Nov.-1960, May
    - Henderson, Sandy, 1948-1950
    - Helming, James, 1948-1949
    - Herschlag, 1952-1958
    - Herschlag, 1959, Oct.
    - Hickman, W. B., 1949-1950
    - Hicks, J. R., 1952-1958
    - Hicks, Ursula, 1950-1952
    - Hirsch, W. A., 1949-1951
    - Holland, Edward, 1961, Aug.-1962, Jan.
    - Hoos, Sidney, 1962, June-July
    - Hoselitz, Bert F., 1948, Apr.-1955, Jan.
    - H.U. (Hebrew University):
    - Early Correspondence: Senator, etc., 1945, Feb.-1947, July 1950-1956,et al
    - University Business, 1950-1956
    - International. Conference on Science in the Advancement of New States,1959, July-1960, Nov.
    - Jaffe, William, 1954, Dec.-1955, Nov.
    - Jaszi, George, 1957, May-1958, Jan.
    - Johnson, Gale, 1948, Sept.-1951, Jan.
    - Johnson, Harry, 1951, Nov.-1962, Oct. (Box 28)
    - Jorgenson,1961,Fall
    - Jorgenson, 1962, Mar.
    - Journal of Political Economy, 1952, Mar.
    - Kahn, R. F., 1951, Dec.-1958, Oct.
    - Kalecki, 1951, Mar.
    - Kaplan, Abbot, 1950, June-Aug.
    - Kaplan, A. D. H., 1955-1956
    - Kessler, A., 1949-1951,May
    - Klein, 1949, June-1956, Aug.
    - Klein, Lawrence R., 1961, June-1962, May
    - Koopmans, 1948, Nov.-Dec.
    - Kuenne, 1954, Dec.-1960, Feb.
    - Kuenne, R. S., 1961, Oct.-1962, Jan.
    - Kurihara, Kenneth, 1951, Oct.-1959
    - Kurimura, Yisikichi, 1949, Sept.-1951, Mar.
    - Kuznets, 1952-1963
    - Lange, Oscar, 1957, May-1965, June
    - Laskey, Gordon, 1961, Aug.
    - Leontief, Wassily, 1946, Nov.-1950, Mar.
    - Lerner, A., 1960, July-Aug.
    - Levhari, David, 1961, Dec.-1962, Nov.
    - Liberman, Robert, 1953, Mar.-Apr.
    - Liviatan, Nissan, 1961, Aug.-1962, July
    - Liviatan, Nissan, 1961, Dec.-1962, March
    - Liviatan, Nissan, 1962, May-1963, July
    - Lloyd, Cliff, 1952, Mar.-1953, Aug.
    - Machlup, Fritz, 1950-1954
    - Machlup, Fritz, 1952, Mar.-1953, Aug.
    - Mann, Harold, 1962, July-Aug.
    - Marginal Utility and Income, 1960
    - Marschak, 1949-1960
    - Marty, Alvin, 1962, May
    - Material on Israeli National Income Until1957
    - Matthews, R. C., 1961-1963
    - McManus, 1956, Dec.-1960, Apr.
    - Means, G. C., 1957, Jan.-Mar.
    - Measurement in Economics, 1961, Oct.-1962, June
    - Mercantilism and Readmission of Jews, 1946, Mar.-Dec.
    - Merrill Center, 1958, Feb.-1960, Aug.
    - Metzler, Lloyd, 1949, July-1952, Sept.
    - Mints, Lloyd, 1950, July-1951, Jan.
    - MIP (Money, Interest and Prices:1949Beginnings), 1954, July-1962, Apr.
    - MIP, 1956:
    - Raw Materials for Notes on Lit., 1931-1951,July
    - Students' Remarks, 1960, Dec.-1963, Nov.
    - MIP, 1958, Dec.-1963, Dec.
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1953
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-1964 (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1957, Aug.-1958, May
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1958, May-1958, Dec.
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1961, Dec.-1962, May
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence:
    - U.S. Dept. of Agriculture,1961
    - Falk Project - Request for Funding
    - Invitations, 1961-1962
    - AEA Paper - Correspondence,1962
    - Moore, Basil J. - Copy of Paper on Theory of Finance
    - Conference on Monetary Economics - Correspondence,1962
    - Mishan, E. J., 1958, Nov.-1962
    - Modern Economic History of the Middle East: Course Outlines, Bibliography and Other
    - Correspondence, 1960, Feb.-1960, Jul.
    - Modigliani, Franco, 1947, Aug.-1965, Nov.
    - Monetary and Price Developments in Israel, 1953, Aug.
    - Morag, 1952, Oct.-1961, Jan.
    - Morgan, Theodore, 1948-1950,Apr.
    - Mosak, Jacob, 1949, Dec.-1950, Apr.
    - Mundlak, Yair, 1962, June-Aug.
    - Mundlak, Yair, undated
    - Negishi, Takashi, 1962, Dec.-1963, Sept.
    - Newspaper Articles and Lectures, 1949, July-1953, Mar.
    - Nissan, 1955-1956
    - Noam, Michael, 1961-1962
    - Notes on Lecture Patinkin Delivered on Opening of Tel Aviv School of Economics, 1959, Nov. 9
    - Patinkin: Correspondence During Sabbatical Year, 1961, Aug.-1962, Jan.
    - Patinkin: Personal Early Years, 1930, Dec.-1949, Feb.
    - Personal Correspondence, 1957, Sept.-1958, Dec.
    - Personal Correspondence, 1958, Dec.-1959, Dec.
    - Personal Correspondence, 1960, Jan.-1960, Dec.
    - Personal Correspondence and Press Clippings, 1960, May-1961, Oct.
    - Price Flexibility, 1948, Nov.-Dec.
    - Project Proposals, 1959, May-1961, Jun.
    - Recommendations, 1948, Mar.-1959
    - Reder, 1956, July-1961, May
    - Referee Reports, 1953, Sept.-Nov.
    - Reprint Requests, 1961, Nov.-1962, April
    - Requests - Paper, 1962, Jan.
    - Riemer, 1948-1955
    - Riemer, S., 1962
    - Robbins' Seminar, 1956-1957 (Box 30)
    - Robinson, E. A. G., 1952, Nov.
    - Rodrovitch, 1958
    - Rothenberg, Jerome, 1961, Oct.-1962, March
    - Row, Peterson:
      - Company, 1954, July-1960, Apr.
      - Heydendahl, 1954, Dec.-1957, Mar.
      - Dahlskog, 1955, Feb.-Mar.
    - Samuelson, P. A., 1946, Oct.-Dec.
    - Searle, John R., 1961-1962
    - Seligman, Lester, 1961
    - Stein, Herbert, 1948, Sept.-1949, Jan.
    - Stigler, George, 1950, Aug.-Oct.
    - Students' Seminar Papers, 1959, Dec.-1961, May
    - Tsiang, S. C., 1960, Jan.-Mar.
    - Turvey, Ralph, 1951, Sept.
    - Two Papers by A. L. Gaathon,1958
    - Unger, Jerome, 1962
    - University of Chicago:
      - Ph.D. Dissertation,1946
      - Ideas for Articles,1946(?)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1948, Feb.
      - Professors, 1950, June-1952
      - Term Papers,1966
      - Appointment and Teaching, 1947, July-Aug.
    - University of Illinois, 1948, July-1951, Apr.
    - Unpublished Articles
    - Valavanis, Stefan, 1956, Apr.
    - Weitz, Ra'anan: Misc.,1962
    - Wonnacott, Paul, 1957, July-1959, June
    - Work in Progress, 1961-1962
    - Work on Papers, 1961, March-1962, July
    - Works - Patinkin, 1961, June-1962, June
    - Yaron, Dan, 1962
    - Yehuda LAVA, 1961, July-Oct
    - Zionism, 1947, May-1948, Feb.
    - Zippori, E., 1953, Oct.-Dec.
  - 1958-1977 (Bulk 1964-1977)and undated
    - Abraham Barstein Legacy, 1965, Jan.-1965, Aug. (Box 30)
    - Articles on Money from Encyclopedia
    - Barkai, Haim, 1968, Mar.-July, 1968
    - Berkeley Sabbatical--Official Correspondence, 1960, Nov.-1962, Oct.
    - Berkeley Sabbatical--Correspondence, 1962, Feb.-Jun.
    - Bibliography (Box 31)
    - Book Orders, 1958, Dec.-1970, Dec.
    - Brandeis, Dec. 1965-1966,June
    - Brechling - Paris IEA Conference, 1962, Apr.-1964, Dec.
    - Brunner, Karl, 1968
    - Comments on J. Baruh's Paper Investment in Education,1964, Oct.
    - Committee for Examining Methods of Reporting Means of Payment, 1963, Sept.-1964, Aug.
    - Committee on the Problems of the Economy, 1973, Dec.-1974, May
    - Committee to Examine Institutes of Higher Learning, 1966, Dec.-1971, Aug.
    - Committee to Examine the Plan for Establishing an Institute for Higher Education in the Neger (Beersheba University Committee), 1964, July-1966, Sept.
    - Committee to Research the Development of the Israeli Occupied Territories, 1967-1972
    - Correspondence, 1963, Jan.-1963, Dec.
    - Correspondence, 1964, Feb.-1965
    - Correspondence, 1965, Apr.-1965, Dec.
    - Correspondence During Trips Abroad,1966, Jul.-1973, Dec.
    - Correspondence: Personal, 1965, Mar.-1967, Apr.
    - Correspondence - Students (Including Recommendations), 1959, Feb.-1966, Dec. (Box 32)
    - Dean, Faculty of Social Sciences and Dept. of Economics, Hebrew University
    - Correspondence, 1963, Jan.-1965, Sept.
    - Discussions on the State Budget,1966
    - Drèze, J., 1966, July-1967, June
    - Dvora, 1967, Oct.-1968, May
    - Econometric Society, May,1964-Dec. 1968
    - Econometric Society, 1969, Jan.-1970, June
    - Econometric Society, 1969, May-1973, Mar.
    - Economics, 1967, Jan.
    - The Economists' Team Column in "Ma'Ariv," 1971, Sept.-1973, Jan.
    - Eisenstadt, S. N., 1968
    - Fauvel, L. (International Economic Association), 1968, Feb.-June
    - Faxen, Karl-Olof, 1968, April-June
    - Frank Knight as Teacher, 1973, May-1974, Nov.
    - Freund, Shoshana, 1967, Nov.-1968, July
    - Friedman, Milton, Correspondence, 1959-1968
    - Friedman, Milton, on the Quantity Theory, 1971, June-1973, Oct. (Box 33)
    - Grunfeld Festschrift, 1963, Jan.-1970 Oct.
    - Haifa Annexe of Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1966, Jan.-1966, Oct.
    - Harrod, R. F., 1969-1972
    - Harvard University, Center for Middle Eastern Studies Colloquium, 1969, Apr.-1970, Feb.
    - Hebrew Encyclopedia, 1959, Jun.-1968, Apr.
    - Hebrew University - Committee for Development and Construction, 1971, July-1972, Jan.
    - HOPE and Economic Journal Keynes Conference, 1976, Feb.-1975, July
    - International Economic Association (IEA), (6 folders)
      - IEA, 1961, Apr.-1964, June
      - IEA, 1964, July-1966, Aug.
      - IEA, 1966, July-1968, Aug.
      - IEA, 1968, Sept.-1969, Oct.
      - IEA, 1969, July-1970, July
      - IEA, 1970, June-1972, Apr.
    - International Encyclopaedia of the Social Sciences, 1961, Apr.-1968, Mar. (Box 34)
    - Invitations, 1963, Dec.-1966, June
    - Invitations, 1967, Sept.-1969, Oct.
    - Invitations, 1972-1975
    - Invitations to Lecture,1966, Jul.-1967, Sept.
    - Israel Academy of Sciences and Humanities, 1969, Apr.-1973, July
    - Israel Academy of Sciences and Humanity, 1963, Sept.-1969, Jan.
    - Israeli-Arab Conflict, 1969, Dec.-1973, Nov.
    - Knight, Frank, 1968, Nov.
    - Kop, Yaakov, 1968, April-June
    - Levhari, David, 1967, Dec.-1968, July
    - Levhari, David and Don Patinkin, 1967
    - Liviatan, Nissan, 1961, Aug.-1964, Mar.
    - Local Correspondence, 1967, Oct.-1969, Apr.
    - MIT, 1968 (Box 35)
    - Media Articles and Interviews,1968,Jun.-1973, Jun.
    - Miscellaneous, 1968, Jan.-June
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1966, Jan.-Oct.
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1966, Nov.-1967, Oct.
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969, Apr.-1971, Jan.
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971, Jan.-1973, Mar.
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1973, Mar.-1975, Aug.
    - Miscellaneous Personal,1968, Jun.-1970, Aug.
    - Monetary and Price Theory Courses,1960, Jul.-1972, Feb.
    - Money, Interest, and Prices (MIP), 1964, Jan.-1965, Sept.
    - MIP, 1965, Sept.-1967, Nov. (Box 36)
    - MIP 2nd edition, 1967, Nov.-1974, May
    - Mundlak, Yair, 1968, Feb.-June
    - The National and University Institute of Agriculture: Centre for Comparative Studies on Agricultural Development, 1960, May-1966, Oct.
    - National Council for Research and Development, 1961, June-1967, May
    - National Science Foundation, 1968, May-June
    - Niehans, Jürg, 1968, Mar.-1972, Jan.
    - OECD Falk, 1964, Mar.-1972, Feb.
    - On the Nature of the Monetary Mechanism, 1967-1968
    - Overseas Correspondence,1967, Jun.-1969, Oct.
    - Personal Correspondence, 1967, Apr.-1968, Sept.
    - Personal Correspondence, 1970, May-1973, May
    - Personal Correspondence and Press Clippings, 1962, May-1963, May
    - Personal Correspondence and PrEss Clippings,1963, Jun.-1965, Mar.
    - Pines, David, 1968, March-April
    - Proposal for the Creation of a Center for International Affairs,1970,Jul.
    - The Quantity of Money, 1968, April-June
    - Raw Material for Article on Dwelling Prices, 1968-1971
    - Referee's Reports/ Book Review Request, 1969, Jan.-1973, Jun.
    - Rehavoth Committee, 1969, Aug.-1973, Sept. (Box 37)
    - Requests for Advice on Economic Planning, 1966, Mar.-1972, May
    - Research Grants, 1960, Sept.-1964, Feb.
    - Research Grants, 1971, Aug.-1973, Aug.
    - [Sidramski?], 1968, April
    - Sosnick, 1968, May-July
    - Stein, Jerome, 1967, Sept.-1968, June
    - Stigler, George, 1972, June-1972, Aug.
    - Stone, Julius, 1967, May-1968, August